So let's see an example of what it looks like to chain
让我们通过一个例子
promises together in a real code situation.
看看在实战中如何链接 promises
So here we see the code we're used to where we make up
这是之前的代码
fake API call in this instance to a web API that we've set up.
我们向臆造的 Web API 发起了一个请求
But what's new here is that we now use
和之前不同
the then syntax after this complete successfully to make a post-request.
我们在请求成功返回后用到了 then 再发起一个 POST 请求
Now if we track this post-request,
看一下这个 POST 请求
we see that we're sending a route which is,
请求的路由是 addAnimal
add the animal and then an object which holds the data that we want to send.
然后传入一个持有数据的对象
Now, this data is based on the data that we got back from the web API call,
这个对象包含两部分 一部分数据是请求 Web API 后返回的
that then function passes that data for us here,
通过 then 函数直接透传进来
so that we can say that we want to send data.animal, data.fact.
因此直接使用 data.animal data.fact 引用
Then here, we see it's just fav because that is not from the web API itself,
这里只有一个 fav 它不是从 Web API 拿到的
that is right from our UI and it's something that our user will have entered themselves.
而是来自用户在界面上的输入
Coming down to our postData call here,
再看看 postData 函数
it's pretty similar to what we've seen,
和前面的代码看起来很像
which is it's an async call that's going to fetch the URL that's passed to it,
依然是一个异步调用 使用 fetch 发起请求
do our work for us and then return that new data.
请求成功后返回数据
But to really get an idea what's going on under the hood,
为了弄清楚背后到底发生了什么
let's go look at our server.
我们看一下服务器端
In the server code,
在服务器代码中
we can see that we've created a post route, which is addAnimal.
创建了一个 POST 路由 addAnimal
Now, when we call this from our code here,
当在客户端代码中向这个路由发起请求时
addAnimal, we're going to create a new entry in
就在应用端点
our data endpoint using the request.body that comes back to us.
使用 request.body 中的数据添加了一条记录
So req.body, in fact,
req.body 到底是什么呢
let's lock it out so we get an idea of what's happening.
我们把它打印出来看看
Because we changed our server,
修改了服务器端代码后
we need to restart the server,
要重启服务器使其生效
then we'll refresh our web browser.
同时刷新浏览器
Now we're just going to test something out.
现在来测试一下
So here we can see that req.body comes back as animal;
req.body 的打印结果如下
So to build our entry in our app endpoint,
为了在应用端点新加一条记录
we're going to create an entry that uses req.body.animal,
我们使用 req.body.animal
which is lion, req.body.fact,
它的值是 lion req.body.fact
which is lions are fun,
它的值是 lions are fun
and req.body.fav, which in this instance,
req.body.fav
is just the word test.
它的值是 test
Then we're going to push all that in the new entry into animal data,
然后把这条记录加入数组 animalData
which is here and this is acting as
在这里 它是我们的
our API endpoint from which we can gather data and do what we want.
API 端点 我们从这里获取数据使用
So going back to our client side code from our server code,
让我们从服务器再回到客户端
we can see that within the then function,
在 then 函数里
the post function will wait for the data it needs and then will execute.
post 函数会等待数据返回后再执行
Let's test it out with something more serious.
让我们再认真地测试一下
Let's say, 'Lions are
输入 Lions are
the best dinner guests for an April affair'.
the best dinner guests for an April affair
My favorite thing about lions.
这是我最喜欢的有关狮子的趣闻
Then we press "Go."
然后点击 Go 按钮
We can see that after making our request,
请求发出后
which we receive from the web API,
从 Web API 得到的数据为
If we look here,
看这里
we can see that from our app endpoint,
从应用端点打印出的信息里
we also have fav,
还包含 fav
'Lions are the best dinner guests'.
Lions are the best dinner guests
Coming back over to our code,
回到代码
we can see that by using the then keyword syntax,
使用 then 函数
we're able to do one thing which is make a request for information,
我们可以在发送请求
and then we're able to do another once we have
并等待其成功返回后
back a successfully resolved version of that.
发起另一次请求
So in this case,
拿这个例子来说
once we get back the data from fake animal data,
从 fakeAnimalData 拿到数据后
then we take that data and we create a post from it.
我们使用它又发起了一个 POST 请求
Now, what if we wanted to do one more thing?
如果我们还想做点什么怎么办
What if we wanted to chain another promise that said
比如请求到数据并 POST 后
after we get the data and we post the data,
再链接一个 promise
what if we want to get the data that we've posted and update our UI with it?
使用 POST 后的数据更新用户界面
That is, what if we want to use dynamically produced data in our static web page?
也就是说如何在静态网页上使用动态数据
We'll learn how to do that next.
且听下回分解